Rob here.
我是罗布
So I have a little confession for you today.
今天我要向您坦白。
I've been using the data binding system
我正在使用数据链接系统
in Polymer for almost two years now but,
在《聚合物》杂志上将近两年，
up until very recently, I didn't actually know how it worked.
但是直到最近我才知道它是如何工作的。
Sure, I could use the binding syntax
我当然可以使用链接结构
to pass data around inside of my app but,
在我的应用程序内传递数据
because I didn't understand what was going on under the hood,
但是由于我对执行机制缺乏了解
it sort of all felt like magic to me
对我来说似乎有点神秘。
and, ultimately, that made the application a lot harder
这最终使纠正错误变得困难
to debug.
应用程序。
So I wanted to create this series of videos
所以我想拍这一系列的视频
so you could understand how bindings
这样您就可以了解绑定的工作方式
are working in your own app.
在您的应用程序内部。
Now to do this, we're going to have
要掌握这一点，我们必须开始
to first know about these things called binding annotations.
了解有关链接的注释。
These are the little symbols that you write in your HTML
它们被定义为您在HTML中键入的小图标
to tell Polymer that you want to create a binding at that spot.
告诉Polymer您要在此站点上创建链接。
One way annotations-- which are signified by square brackets--
和单向注释
allow you to flow data from a host element down to a target,
用方括号标记，您可以流式传输来自主机元素的数据
but never back from the target up to the host.
到目标，但没有从该目标返回到主机。
To do something like that, you'll
为了做这样的事情，
want to use two-way annotations, or what are sometimes
您需要使用双向注释
called automatic annotations.
或有时称为自动注释。
This lets the host and the target
有了它，您可以托管和定位
pass data back and forth.
来回滚动数据。
Now I'll explain this a little bit more in a minute
我现在将在稍后详细解释
but first, I just want to stop and think
但是首先我要引导
what's actually going on inside of my app
关于我的应用程序内部已经发生的事情
when Polymer encounters an annotation?
当Polymer找到注释时。
So when Polymer first sees your element,
最初，当Polymer找到您的商品时
you're trying to register it and everything, Polymer's
当您尝试记录时，它将进行分析
going to parse your element's template
元素模板
and actually look for these nodes with these binding
他将寻找带注释的这些节点
annotations.
用于绑定。
And when it finds these sort of binding annotations,
当他找到链接的这些注释时，
it's going to create what it calls property effects.
会产生所谓的属性效果。
And a property effect is a little object
该属性的影响很小
that knows which node in the DOM to update whenever
已知DOM中的节点类型已更新
this property has changed.
每当此属性更改时。
So, in this example, Polymer is going
因此，在此示例中，创建了聚合物
to create a property effect for this div right here
div属性的效果直接在这里
and another property effect for this paper input element.
而此纸张输入元素的另一个属性效果。
So we'll have two property effects.
因此，我们将产生两种效果。
And all of these property effect objects get stored in an array.
所有属性效果对象都存储在数组中。
Now I like to think of that array of property effects
我现在想考虑一下这一系列的属性效果
as kind of like a checklist of actions
就像动作清单一样
that need to run any time that property updates.
必须在属性更新时执行。
And you can actually go and look at this actual array,
如果需要，可以实际查看此实际数组。
You can hop into the dev tools and this is an element
您可以转到开发人员工具，看到的是您创建的项目。
You can use that little trick that I've shown you before,
您可以使用我之前向您展示的小技巧，
where you can select it in the Elements Panel and then just do
您可以在“项目”面板中选择项目
dollar sign zero and type ._propertyeffects.
然后输入“ $ 0”，然后输入“ ._propertyeffects”
Now this is a private part of Polymer.
这是聚合物中的一个特殊部分
It's not something we should be messing with,
禁止篡改它，但我们可以对其进行检查。
It's kind of fun.
很好玩
And it'll give you this object with this array.
您将看到此对象与此数组。
And you can see here, there's two objects inside of here.
您可以在此处看到两个对象。
These are our two property effects
我们创建的两个效果
and you can see a little bit of info about the property effect
关于财产本身的影响的信息很少。
itself.
这是文本属性效果。
It's set to use curly brace mode, which I'm assuming
设置为使用包围模式
means it's in some sort of two way binding mode, et cetera.
我认为这是一种双向连接。
So it's just kind of interesting that you can go in
所以进入这里很有趣
and you can kind of inspect this checklist a little bit.
您可以检查一下此清单。
Now looking back at our example, I'm
回到我们的例子，我现在将
going to simplify things just a little bit so,
为了简化一点
there's less markup to look at.
直到我们检查较少的编码。
So this is our template and this is our Polymer element
这是我们的模板，这是元素的定义
definition.
聚合物。
Now the other thing that Polymer is
Polymer会做的另一件事
going to do, aside from creating property effects,
创建效果属性旁边
is it's going to create a setter for this property that we've
是为属性创建一个setter函数
got here, this foo property.
我们在这里拥有任何foo属性。
So you can see we've got this little set foo setter down here
如您所见，我们在此处删除了set foo setter
and, if you're not familiar with syntax like this,
如果您不习惯这样的结构
I'll link to a little doc on MDN that
我将链接到MDN上的一个小文档
talks about JavaScript setters.
它讨论了JavaScript setter的功能。
And I should stress, this is not the exact syntax
我必须强调，这不是实际的结构
that Polymer uses it.
由聚合物使用；
It does it kind of a little differently at runtime
运行时几乎没有差异
but, essentially, what happens is, once it's created property
但是创建效果后会发生什么
effects for a property, it also creates
对于财产，它还会创建
a setter for that property.
该属性的Setter函数。
And inside of this setter, there's
在此setter函数中，
a few interesting things that take place.
一些有趣的事情发生了。
The first is, anytime the property changes,
首先是，只要属性发生变化，
Polymer is going to do what it calls dirty checking.
Polymer进行所谓的检查更改。
So a dirty check is when you compare an old value
比较旧值时会检查更改
to a new value and you see if they've actually changed.
新值，看看是否已经有更改。
And what Polymer does is it actually
聚合物已经在做什么
stores this foo property in a super duper private variable
此foo属性存储在一个出色的私有变量中
called underscore underscore data underscore underscore.
被称为“ _ _ data_ _”。
And you can kind of poke around and see this in the dev tools,
您也可以在开发人员工具中进行搜索和查看。
It stores the original value over there
原始值存储在此处
and, whenever someone changes the property,
当有人改变财产时，
changes our foo property, if they change
即通过更改foo的属性
it through JavaScript or changing the attribute
例如，JavaScript或通过更改属性
or something like that, it's first
或类似，将首先检查
going to check to see if the old value and the new value
在旧的和新的价值观中
are different.
不一样
Because if they're the same, there's
因为如果两个值没有不同，
no point in doing a bunch of work.
努力是没有意义的。
If they are different, if we do pass the dirty check,
使用检查更改检测到差异时
then we're going to hold onto that new value.
我们将保持这一新价值。
And the next thing after that is we're just
接下来的事情
going to loop over all of our property effects,
是我们重复属性的所有作用吗
give them that new value, and then
并赋予它新的价值
that tells them to go update these nodes in the DOM.
然后，我们邀请他们更新DOM中的这些节点。
So if this is sort of our fake checklist of property effects--
因此，这大概是一个属性选择清单
and again, this is all just pseudo code,
这也是假设所有代码
but this is kind of what they look
但这是他们的外表，
like, right-- someone passes in a new value,
有人介绍了新的价值，
we say, hey it's different from the old value.
但是我们发现它与新价值不同。
Cool, let's hold on to it.
所以我们保留它。
Now let's just start walking through that checklist
现在让我们检查选择列表
of properties and we'll say, all right, let's set that new value
这些属性并分配该新值
up here on this div.
在这里。
Cool, done.
做完了
Next one, let's set that new value
现在让我们设置新值
over here in the input element and so on and so on.
在输入元素中，依此类推。
And if these elements, within themselves,
如果这些要素
have property effects, those will kick off and run
它具有属性效果，因此您可以开始工作。
and basically that's how data gets passed all the way down
这就是数据传递的方式
the line, through all the different children.
它遍历所有各种依赖元素的整个过程。
Now I'm sure some of you are seeing this and saying, well,
我确定您现在已经看过了，您会问：
what about the property's object?
那属性对象呢？
Because I know this is also part of the mix, right?
因为我知道这是其中的一部分，对吗？
How does this thing get involved?
但是，这和它有什么关系呢？
Well the property's object basically allows
好吧，属性对象基本上允许
you to add what I think of as sort of like metadata
您添加我认为是某种元数据的内容
to your property setter, if you will.
在需要时为您的财产设置功能。
So here's our example again and I've got this property's object
再回到我们的例子，我有这个属性对象
now and I've got my foo property inside of here.
还有foo属性。
And the setter is already set up,
设定器功能已经设定。
so it's going to first dirty check for new values,
因此，将首先检查新的价值变化，
it's going to run the property effects,
并打开属性效果
if things are different.
如果值不同。
And let's say, in my properties object,
让我在我的属性对象中
I add an observer, right?
添加了观察者功能。
And I say, OK, well when foo changes,
然后我选择确定，当foo更改时，
I want you to run this observer function right here.
我希望您在此处运行观察器功能。
Well what happens is, inside of the setter,
在setter函数中发生了什么
Polymer is just going to literally call that function.
聚合物调用该函数。
And I know it seems like it might
我知道似乎还有更多歧义
be doing something more magical but, really, this is just it.
在此过程中，事实就是如此。
It's just going to call that function as soon as it's
完成后会调用该函数
done doing any other work.
比任何其他业务。
If you give it a notify true flag--
如果您在旁边添加true标签以进行通知
and this enables two way binding throughout the Polymer system--
在整个Polymer系统中启用了双向连接，
well what this is actually doing is it's just calling this
所以实际发生的是称之为this.fire
.fire, which dispatches an event and it's just dispatching
那发送一个事件叫做
an event called foo-changed and passing along the value,
“ foo-changed”并传递值，
the brand new value.
我的意思是全新的价值。
So any time you do this on a property,
因此，无论何时使用属性进行此操作，
Polymer will always create this sort of event dispatch
Polymer将始终创建此事件提交活动。
and the event is always called something dash changed.
事件名称始终由事物组成，然后“更改”。
Whatever the property name is, dash changed.
无论属性名称是什么，都添加“ -changed”。
And this is really interesting because it
这真的很有趣
means if you yourself are binding to an element,
因为这意味着如果您要链接到某个项目，
like here I'm binding to paper input's value attribute, what
链接纸张输入值属性
Polymer does when it first boots up is it says,
所以聚合物在启动时会说
OK, I found an annotation here.
好吧，我在这里找到了注释。
Let me create a property effect and everything.
让我创建一个属性效果，
Are we bound to some other elements attribute?
我们是否有其他功能的链接？
Ah, yes, we are.
是的
I can see that we're bound to this value thing.
我可以看到我们有一个指向该值的链接。
So if this then fires a event called value changed,
因此，当这触发一个称为“值更改”的事件时
then hearing that event is going to tell me to update
该事件的标志将邀请我更新
this property right here.
该属性就在这里。
So really that's all that's happening in properties
这就是属性之间真正发生的全部
to a binding system.
以及任何连接系统。
Your element fires a changed event,
您的物品触发了变化的事件
some other element that is bound to it
另一个关联的项目监听
listens to that changed event, and it updates its own property
然后，此变量更新其属性
because of that.
因此。
Now here I've got a two way binding
这里我们有双向连接
and so you can actually see the system in play
您已经可以看到您刚才解释的系统
that I just described.
可以用
So I'm going to go in here, and this
我要搬到这里
is a representation of our element,
这是我们元素的代表。
and I can type into the paper input field
我可以在纸张输入栏中输入
and it's going to fire those changed events
这些事件改变了
and then that means I update foo, and, because it's
这意味着我的foo更新
going to go through and play through all of my property
因为它将移动并通过所有效果
effects, that means the foo gets updated right here as well.
我的属性，也在这里更新foo。
And you can see that here.
您可以在这里看到它。
So they end up matching.
最后，它们是匹配的。
But what if I'm using a one way binding, right?
但是，如果我使用单向连接怎么办？
So here I'm using square brackets now,
在这里我用方括号
instead of the curly braces.
而不是花括号。
Well that just tells Polymer hey, don't set up the event
这告诉Polymer不要成为听众
listener for value changed.
变量值事件。
That's really all that happens there.
而这一切都是真的。
So now I go in, I type in this input field
我现在将移至此处并在此输入字段中输入
and, because I'm not listening for those events,
由于我不向这些事件分发消息，
I don't hear anything and this property up here
我什么也收不到，财产留在这里
remains what it always was.
一如既往。
So we're not pushing any new data up there.
我们不会在其中包含任何新数据。
So the last thing I want to talk about are read only properties.
我最后要谈的是只读属性。
So you can set a read only flag and that
您可以设置一个只读标志
means that an outsider using your element
这意味着没有外部用户可以拥有您的商品
can't push data into it, in any way.
以任何方式插入数据。
So what happens there is Polymer just doesn't
所以这里发生的是聚合物不会产生
create the setter, right?
二传手功能，对吗？
It doesn't create a public setter at all,
根本不会创建通用设置器功能
because we don't want someone accidentally calling that.
因为我们不希望别人意外召回。
And instead, because it does still internally
相反，因为它仍然需要
need to work with that data, it creates a little private setter
在内部使用该数据，它会创建一个小的私有设置器函数
that it prefixes with this underscore.
其名称以前缀“ _”开头。
And you can actually work with these.
这些实际上可以使用。
This is the actual syntax that it uses.
这是他使用的实际结构。
So if you need to work with your read only property
因此，如果您需要使用“只读”
from within your element, you can use this private setter
您可以在商品中使用此特殊的设置器功能
to update it and that is how that works.
要执行更新，这是作用机制。
All right, so now you know the basics of data binding.
好了，现在您知道了数据绑定的基础。
But there's still a lot of cool stuff
但是还有很多奇妙的事情
to cover-- binding two arrays and deeply nested
例如连接两个数组和深层嵌套的对象
objects and computer properties and change records
以及计算机属性和更改日志
and notifications and, well, anyway, I'll
和注意，无论如何
save that for another episode.
我将其推迟另一集。
Now if you've enjoyed this video, be sure to go down
如果您喜欢视频，别忘了下来
and click the Subscribe button, because that's actually how
然后点击“订阅”按钮，因为实际上
we get to keep making these.
是什么使我们步入正轨。
Also if you have questions for me,
如果您有问题要问我，
leave them down in the comments or ping me
写在评论中或询问我
on a social network of your choosing, hash tag #askPolymer.
在使用主题标签“ #askPolymer”的社交网络上。
As always, thank you so much for watching.
和往常一样，感谢您的收看。
I'll see you next time.
待会见。